

EXPERTISE

- Proficient in problemsolving and utilizing analytical skills.
- Knowledgeable in both software and hardware.
- Experienced in web development.
- Capable of database modeling.
- Proficient in software testing and debugging.
- Experienced in technical support.
- Capable of troubleshooting hardware and software issues.

CONTACT



+971545673549

+916238497970

anupamasnc@gmail.com



Anupama C Nair

Software Engineer

Profile

As an IT professional with a Master's degree in Computer Science, I have over three years of experience as a software developer in PHP and 1 year of experience as a customer support executive with IT administration responsibilities.

Experience

Software Engineer

Pepperberg Software Solutions -India I Jan 2020- Apr 2022

- Developed and maintained web applications using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Conducted code reviews and implemented improvements to ensure optimal performance and scalability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and deploy software projects.
- Resolved technical issues reported by customers and provided timely solutions.
- Conducted software testing and implemented bug fixes as needed.
- Maintained and updated documentation for software development processes and procedures.

Customer Support executive

BLS International -UAE I Nov 2017- Oct 2018

- Entering and managing data accurately and efficiently using various software programs and systems.
- Providing customer support and troubleshooting technical issues related to the company's products and services.
- Maintaining data integrity and security by ensuring accuracy and up-to-date information.
- Collaborating with other departments to ensure effective communication and resolution of issues.
- Maintaining accurate records of customer interactions and technical issues.
- Supporting new application submissions and IT administration as needed.
- Identifying opportunities for process improvement and contributing to continuous improvement efforts.
- Staying up-to-date with new products and services to effectively support customers.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

- Master in Computer Applications
- Bachelor in Computer
 Applications

LANGUAGES

- English
- Malayalam
- Tamil
- Hindi

Nationality -Indian

JR. Software Engineer

Pepperberg Software Solutions I Jan 2015- May 2016

- Modify and improve software for debugging and better performance.
- Develop a local search website using PHP Symfony and MySQL.
- Write clean, well-documented code that is easy to maintain.
- Collaborate with other developers for integration of new features and participate in code reviews to ensure code quality and maintainability.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Solid knowledge and experience in Website development.
- Proficient in PHP, HTML 5 and CSS
- Excellent in website and software application designing, building and maintaining
- Experience in developing websites with PHP Symfony framework
- Strong knowledge of PHP Laravel framework
- Solid knowledge and experience in software testing and validation
- Proficient in MySQL and SQL Server
- Skilled at JavaScript, Node.js, and Express
- Proficient in Database Management Systems
- Skilled at Design and development of databases
- Experience with WAMP and XAMPP

PROJECTS HANDLED

WWW.ONTRIX.COM

An e-Commerce website with client login and dashboard.
 Backend has CRM integrated with it. This web application is developed in Symfony. We had to discuss with client to finalize requirement and develop and deploy it.

TAXI KID

 It was an application for book taxi online, it includes embedding google Map

ONE OTHER MAPPING SITE

• This site tells the user the location where he will get the searched item in the city.